

stefanmisik.com

in linkedin.com/in/stefan-misik

🥷 github.com/stefan-misik



I am a perfectionist developer, researcher, and clean code enthusiast with passion for clarity, intellectual and mathematical rigour in technical and scientific expression. My interests lie in many aspects of embedded and distributed systems - ranging from research to hardware design and embedded software implementation.

Professional Experience

Embedded Software Engineer May 2018 – present — TESCAN BRNO S.R.O. ■ Embedded software development for electron microscope subsystems ■ Implementation of the Test Driven Development and Clean Code practices in embedded software development ■ Design of the build environment allowing for automated testing and building in CI/CD systems ■ Automation of software development-related tasks using python and bash scripts

Research Engineer

Jan. 2017 – Mar. 2018 — CCI PARIS ILE-DE-FRANCE • Collaboration on smart city related research project • review of the scientific literature • mathematical models design • design of simulation platforms • simulation execution and evaluation of results

Software Engineer

Jun. 2014 – Dec. 2016 — BIOSDESIGN S.R.O. ■ Collaboration on couple software development projects in C# and C++ ■ hardware and software integration

Technical Support

Apr. 2013 – Jun. 2014 — HONEYWELL AEROSPACE ■ Work on the Navigation Prototyping Platform ■ development of the embedded part using DEOS Real Time Operating System in C programming language ■ development of PC application for logging measured data in C# ■ software testing ■ hardware and software integration

Skills

Programming Languages C • C++ • C# • Objective-C • Java • Python • MATLAB and Simulink • VHDL • Bash • PHP • SQL • JavaScript • HTML • CSS and SCSS

APIs

Win32 • .NET • POSIX (GNU/Linux) • FreeRTOS • DDC-I DEOS • ANSI C standard library

Tools

GNU Make • GNU Compiler Collection • GNU Debugger • Vim • MS Visual Studio • Cygwin/MinGW • NetBeans IDE • Eclipse • Version Control Tools – Git and Subversion • CI/CD Systems

Theory

System/Control Theory • Calculus • Optimization • Microcontroller powered embedded system design • Real-Time Systems • Operating Systems Principles • Test-Driven Development

Engineering

Digital circuit design • Cryptography • PCB layout • PCB assembly

OS Administration

GNU/Linux • Windows • macOS

Languages

Slovak – native language ■ English – full professional proficiency (C1-C2) ■ German, French – elementary proficiency

Documents Authoring

LATEX MS Office Doxygen Markdown

Graphics & Design

GIMP Inkscape HTML and CSS

Driving

EEA Licence Categories: B1, B, AM



Interests

New technologies • Tech blogging • Writing scripts to automatize menial and repetitive tasks • Philosophy • Playing guitar • Hiking • Gym • Cooking

Education

Doctoral degree (PhD)

2014 – present — Cybernetics, Automation and Measurement at Brno University of Technology • *Final Thesis*: Optimal Scheduling of Resource-Constrained Real-Time Distributed Systems • *Study Abroad*: ESIEE Paris, France (Sep. 2015 – Jun. 2016)

Master's degree (Ing)

2012 – 2014 — Cybernetics, Automation and Measurement at Brno University of Technology • *Final Thesis*: Weather Station with Ethernet Interface

Bachelor's degree (Bc)

2009 – 2012 — Control and Instrumentation at Brno University of Technology ■ *Final Thesis*: Wireless transfer of image between the PCs

2005 – 2009 — Electrical and Electronics Engineering at secondary professional school (Stredná Priemyselná Škola v Trnave)

Publications

Stefan Misik, Jakub Arm, and Zdenek Bradac. Formulation and simulation of receding horizon control over mixed logical dynamical system. In *15th IFAC Conference on Programmable Devices and Embedded Systems - PDeS 2018*, volume 51, pages 390–395. Elsevier BV, 2018. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ifacol. 2018.07.185

Stefan Misik, Zdenek Bradac, and Arben Cela. Reducing usage of the computational resources by event driven approach to model predictive control. *Journal of Electrical Engineering EC*, 68(4):290–298, September 2017. ISSN 1335-3632. doi: https://doi.org/10.1515/jee-2017-0041

Stefan Misik, Arben Cela, and Zdenek Bradac. Distributed systems - a brief review of theory and practice. In *14th IFAC Conference on Programmable Devices and Embedded Systems - PDeS 2016*, pages 133–138, 2016a. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ifacol.2016.12.057

Stefan Misik, Arben Cela, and Zdenek Bradac. Optimal predictive control - a brief review of theory and practice. In *14th IFAC Conference on Programmable Devices and Embedded Systems - PDeS 2016*, pages 133–138, 2016b. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ifacol.2016.12.058

Stefan Misik, Zdenek Bradac, Jakub Arm, and Ladislav Stastny. Embedded telemetry system with data presentation using http and data logging. In *13th IFAC Conference on Programmable Devices and Embedded Systems - PDeS 2015*, pages 101–106, 2015. doi: https://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ifacol.2015.07.015